Guide to the Jeremy Reed Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Jeremy Reed papers
1980-1998
GEN MSS 678
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
19.93
(22 boxes)
The Jeremy Reed Papers document the writing of Jeremy Reed and include drafts of poetry, prose and translations, notebooks containing poetry drafts, correspondence with David Gascoyne, Kathleen Raine, Enitharmon Press, and others, and a small amount of contractual material related to the publishing of Reed's work. The papers include holograph drafts and printouts of most of Reed's writings between the early 1980s and 2007. Most of the drafts are corrected and accompanied by correspondence with editors.
Reed, Jeremy
General note
This finding aid describes a collection that has been acquired by the library in discrete segments over time. The narrative sections of the finding aid provide information about the content and context of the collection. The Collection Contents section provides a general description and a box or folder listing of the various acquisitions of the collection. The Processing Notes section provides information about the way and extent to which the library has processed this collection. The Arrangement section provides information about how material within this collection is organized and tips on how to locate material across various acquisitions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from R. A. Gekoski Booksellers on the George Henry Nettleton Fund and the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1998-2007.
Gift of Jeremy Reed, 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Access to original audiovisual recordings in Boxes 21-22 is restricted. Consult Access Services for information about reference copies.
Arrangement
The papers are organized into six groupings: October 1998 Acquisition, November 1999 Acquisition, September 2002 Acquisition, May 2007 Acquisition, and August 2007 Acquisition, and May 2010 Acquisition. Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time. Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, correspondence can be found in all six groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Jeremy Reed, 1951-
Jeremy Reed, British author, was born March 6, 1951 in Jersey, Channel Islands. A prolific poet, novelist and translator, Reed has authored dozens of volumes of poetry, prose and cultural analysis.
Scope and Contents
The Jeremy Reed Papers document the writing of Jeremy Reed and include drafts of poetry, prose and translations, notebooks containing poetry drafts, correspondence with David Gascoyne, Kathleen Raine, Enitharmon Press, and others, and a small amount of contractual material related to the publishing of Reed's work. The papers include holograph drafts and printouts of most of Reed's writings between the early 1980s and 2007. Most of the drafts are corrected and accompanied by correspondence with editors.
English literature -- 20th Century; Authors, English -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials; Sound recordings; Gascoyne, David, 1916-2001; Raine, Kathleen, 1908-2003; Reed, Jeremy; Enitharmon Press
- October 1998 Acquisition, 1980-1992; (1 box)
  General note
  Formerly classed as Uncat MS Vault 825.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from R. A. Gekoski Booksellers on the George Henry Nettleton Fund, 1998.
  - Gascoyne, David and Judy, correspondence, 1980-1992; 6 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Enclosures include a broadside of the poem "Rondel for the Fourth Decade" and two photographs of David Gascoyne.
- November 1999 Acquisition, 1981-1998; (9 boxes)
  Formerly classed as Uncat MS Vault 871.
  Purchased from R. A. Gekoski Booksellers on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1999.
  - Raine, Kathleen, correspondence, 1981-1990; 15 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, incoming (various), 1980-1996; 17 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, incoming (various), 1980-1997; 8 (Box 3)
  - Lehman, John, correspondence, 1980-1989; 4 (Box 3)
  - Lehman, Rosamond, correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Post cards and photographs, 1982-1996 (Box 3)
  - Sister Midnight, holograph, 1997; 2 (Box 3)
  - Another Tear Falls, holograph, 1998; 4 (Box 3)
  - Waiting for the Man: A Biography of Lou Reed, typescript and editorial correspondence, 1995; 12 (Box 3)
  - Dorian, typescript and editorial correspondence, 1997; 3 (Box 4)
  - Heartbreak Hotel: A novel about Elvis Presley in four volumes, draft, notebooks, holograph, 1996; 4 (Box 4)
    Volume 4 is Titled "The Sun King"
  - Brian Jones: The Last Decadent, draft, holograph, 1998; 3 (Box 4)
  - Chasing Black Rainbows, typescript and editorial correspondence, 1993; 4 (Box 4)
  - The Pleasure Chateau, typescript and contractual agreement, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Blue Rock, typescript, 1985; 3 (Box 4)
  - Erotic stories, typescript, 1997; 3 (Box 4)
  - Bitter Blue, typescript and manuscript, and editorial correspondence, 1996; 3 (Box 4)
  - Unidentified prose, typescript, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Prairies of Fever (translation from Arabic to English), hologrpah and typescript, 1988; 9 (Box 5)
    Accompanied by two notebooks containing translations of Arabic poets
  - Poetry, Madness and Gender, typescript, 1989; 3 (Box 5)
  - Madness: The Price of Poetry, typescript and two corrected drafts, 1989; 6 (Box 5)
  - Isidore, draft and revised copies with typescript, 1990; 8 (Box 5)
  - Red Eclipse, typescript with two drafts, 1989; 7 (Box 6)
  - Lipstick, Sex and Poetry, typescript, 1991; 2 (Box 6)
  - The Conglomerate: Warhol/Bowie/Ballard, typescript, second draft and editorial correspondence, 1993; 6 (Box 6)
  - Inhabiting Shadows: A Novel, typescript, 1990; 2 (Box 6)
  - Delirium: An Appreciation of Arthur Rimbaud, typescript and editorial correspondence, 1991; 3 (Box 6)
  - Novalis: Hymns to the Night (translation from German to English), typescript and editorial correspondence, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Heartbreak Hotel, notebooks, holograph, 1998; 6 (Box 6)
  - Poetry notebooks, holograph, 1988-1989; 34 (Box 7)
  - Poetry notebooks, holograph, 1990-1991; 28 (Box 8)
  - Poetry notebooks, holograph, 1992-1993; 8 (Box 9)
  - Volcano Smoke at Diamond Beach, holograph (copy), typescript and correspondence, 1991 (Box 9)
  - The Coastguard's House, typescript and correspondence, 1990; 2 (Box 9)
  - Montale Translations, typescript and correspondence, 1988-1992; 2 (Box 9)
  - When the Whip Comes Down: A novel about the Marquis De Sade, typescript, 1988; 3 (Box 9)
  - Marc Almond at the Palladium, Mark Almond and Scott Walker, and translation from Lautréamont's Maldoror, holograph, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Baron Fersen, holograph, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Erotic stories, holograph, undated; 2 (Box 9)
  - Essays on Montale and Scott Walker, holograph, and correspondence, 1996 (Box 9)
  - The Pleasure Chateau, Screenplay based on the novel, holograph, undated (Box 9)
  - Jean Genet translations, holograph and typescript, 1995-1998 (Box 9)
  - Pop Stars, typescript and correspondence, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Translations of Jean Genet and Arabic poems, holograph, [1984?] (Box 9)
  - Sweet Sister Lyric, typescript and correspondence, 1995 (Box 9)
- September 2002 Acquisition, 1985-2002; (3 boxes)
  Formerly classed as Uncat MSS 363.
  Purchased from R. A. Gekoski Booksellers on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
  - Chasing Black Rainbows, holograph and printout, circa 1994; 10 (Box 10)
  - Divine Carnage: Death Rites of the Roman Emperors, holograph, 2000; 2 (Box 10)
  - E-mailing Dead Marilyn, holograph, 1999; 5 (Box 10)
  - The last star, holograph, 1999; 2 (Box 11)
  - Marilyn Monroe: The Last 24 Hours, holograph and printout, undated; 2 (Box 11)
  - Pretty Boy, holograph, 2001; 7 (Box 11)
  - The Purple Room, holograph and printout, 1999 (Box 11)
  - Saint Billie, holograph, printout and correspondence, 2001-2002; 5 (Box 11)
  - Poetry notebooks, 1985-1986; 11 (Box 11)
  - Poetry notebooks, 1986-1988; 15 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, incoming (various), 1990-2001; 9 (Box 12)
- May 2007 Acquisition, 2002, 2006; 0.21; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to original audiovisual recordings in Box 22 is restricted. Consult Access Services for information about reference copies.
  Gift of Jeremy Reed, 2007.
  - News from other planets. Jeremy Reed & Tim Mitchell. [London?]: Bastet CD2, 2002 (Box 22)
    1 audio compact disc
  - Jeremy Reed at the Queen Elizabeth Hall. [London?]: Joe DiMaggio Productions, 2006 (Box 22)
- August 2007 Acquisition, 1980-2007; (6 boxes)
  Formerly classed as Uncat MSS 964.
  Purchased from R. A. Gekoski Booksellers on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2007.
  - A Stranger on Earth: The Life and Work of Anna Kavan, holograph, printout, correspondence and audio cassettes, 2000s; 12 (Box 13)
  - Jean Genet: Born to Lose, holograph and printout, 2000s; 3 (Box 13)
  - Black Masses: Lord Lyllian (preface by Jeremy Reed), holograph and printout, 2005 (Box 13)
  - "Millennial Prophecies," holograph, 2000; 2 (Box 13)
  - Essay on Marc Almond, holograph and printout, undated; 2 (Box 13)
  - The Grid, holograph, 2000s; 2 (Box 13)
  - Inferno, translations into English, holograph and printout, undated (Box 13)
  - Orange Sunshine: The Party that Lasted a Decade, holograph and printout, 2000s; 10 (Box 14)
  - "Nothing but a star," holograph, and foreword by J. G. Ballard, printout, 2006-2007 (Box 14)
  - Santos Dumont (screenplay), holograph and typescript, undated; 6 (Box 14)
  - Jean Tardieu translations, holograph, undated (Box 14)
  - Jean Genet translations, printouts and correspondence, 1994 (Box 14)
  - "All or nothing," holograph and printout, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Black Masses: Lord Lyllian, English translation corrected by Jeremy reed, typescript, 2005; 2 (Box 14)
  - Behind Closed Doors, holograph, undated (Box 14)
  - Pretty Boy, printout, contract and correspondence, 2002; 2 (Box 14)
  - The Grid, holograph, 2000s; 4 (Box 15)
  - Poetry notebooks, 1980-1983; 21 (Box 15)
  - "It had to be you" (essay on John Wieners), holograph, typescript and correspondence, 2000s (Box 16)
  - "Two suicides," holograph and printout, undated (Box 16)
  - Rotterdam poetry festival ephemera, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Adored and explored, holograph, printout and photographs of Marc Almond, 2001; 2 (Box 16)
  - Marlowe (notes for a novel), holograph, undated (Box 16)
  - Poetry notebooks, 1984-2005; 21 (Box 16)
  - "Presley sequence" (poems), holograph, undated (Box 17)
  - "As Your Eyes are Blue: Lee Harwood's Collected Poems," proof, 2005 (Box 17)
  - Poems, holograph, undated (Box 17)
  - Correspondence
    - David Deiss (Box 17)
    - Stephen Barber (Box 17)
    - Kathrin Caltridge (Box 17)
    - Bill Corbette (Box 17)
    - Felice Picano (Box 17)
    - George Messo (Box 17)
    - Edmund White (Box 17)
    - Grevel Lindop (Box 17)
    - Lain Sinclair (Box 17)
    - Paul Muldoon (Box 17)
    - David Caddy (Box 17)
    - Robert ? (Box 17)
    - David and Judy Gascoyne (Box 17)
    - John Heath-Stubbs (Box 17)
    - Helen O'Connor (Box 17)
    - Neil Curry (Box 17)
    - Christopher Reid (Box 17)
    - David J. Of Bahaus, 2 (Box 17)
    - Anna X (Box 17)
    - Stephen Stuart-Smith from Enitharmon Press, 3 (Box 17)
    - Marco Livingstone (Box 17)
    - Kathleen Raine (Box 17)
  - "Lover man", correspondence and proofs (Box 17)
  - Correspondence
    - Richard Livermore (Box 17)
    - Will Self (Box 17)
    - Cory Harting (Box 17)
    - Michael ? (Box 17)
    - Matthew Lewis (Box 17)
    - Alan Miles (Box 17)
    - Ian Fadyen (Box 17)
  - Letter: Ted Hughes to Kathleen Raine with printouts (Box 17)
  - Kathleen Raine, "Yeats and the creed of St. Patrick," proof, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Rattray, David, "Les Nouvelles Revelations de l'Etre," typescript (copy), undated (Box 18)
  - Karl Theodor Bluth (1892-1964), correspondence and notes (Box 18)
  - "The Shanachie", print, undated (Box 18)
  - Poems for Temenos, typescript and correspondence, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence from Scot Ryerson about his biography of Marchesa Casati (Box 18)
  - Jean Genet: Born to Lose, printout, 2000s (Box 18)
  - Poems, holograph, undated; 2 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, incoming (various), 8 (Box 18)
- May 2010 Acquisition, 1960s-2010; (3 boxes)
  - Here comes the nice final notebook (Box 19)
  - John Stephen
    - Film synopsis (Box 19)
    - Screenplay synopsis 2 (Box 19)
    - Research notes v. 1 (Box 19)
    - Research notes v. 2 (Box 19)
    - Notes from interviews, 2009 (Box 19)
    - King of Carnaby Street, 2 (Box 19)
    - King of Carnaby Street volume 2 (Box 19)
    - King of Carnaby Street volume 3 (Box 19)
    - King of Carnaby Street volume 4 (Box 19)
    - King of Carnaby Street (Box 19)
    - King of Carnaby Street and the 1960s look: typescript corrected by Bill Franks (Box 19)
  - Johnny remember me, 4 notebooks (Box 19)
  - Carnaby Street photographs, circa 1960s (Box 19)
  - Picadilly Bongo Poetry to be published by Eirtharmon Press, 2010 (Box 19)
  - Saint Derek of Dungeness (Box 19)
  - Almond, Mark, Beautiful Twisted Night, circa 1998-1999 (Box 19)
  - Jeremy Reed Archive details (Box 19)
  - Armstrong, Michael with poetry (Box 20)
  - Armstrong, Michael with poems (Box 20)
  - Balancem, John (Box 20)
  - Benveniste, Asa (Box 20)
  - Eshleman, Clayton (Box 20)
  - unidentified (Box 20)
  - Behind Closed Doors (Box 20)
  - Black magic, Tattoo, Candella and Opening Night Jeremy Reed on Joanna Jones (Box 20)
  - Gimme Shelter
    - London Alien: The Autobiography of a poet volume 1, 2008 Feb (Box 20)
    - Volume 2 Alien: Autobiography of a poet (Box 20)
    - Volume 3 Alien (Box 20)
    - Volume 4 Alien: The Autobiography of a London Poet, 2008 Apr (Box 20)
    - Volume 5 Alien: The London Autobiography, 2008 Apr (Box 20)
    - Volume 6 Alien (Box 20)
    - Alien, 2008 May (Box 20)
    - Alien volume 8, Autobiography of a London poet, undated (Box 20)
    - Weakness for Roses for Norcan volume 9, 2008 Summer (Box 20)
    - Volume 10, 2008 (Box 20)
  - Here comes the nice Notebook, 9 (Box 20)
  - Jeremy Reed Audiocassettes (Box 21)
    Access to original audiovisual recordings in Box 21 is restricted. Consult Access Services for information about reference copies.
    (sound recordings) Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Bill Franks volume 1 (1 of 3 audiocassettes), 2005 November 28; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002109973397)
    - Bill Franks volume 2 (2 of 3 audiocassettes), 2005 December 6; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002109973405)
    - Bill Franks volume 3 (3 of 3 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002109973413)
    - Bill Franks, 2006 July 18; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002109973447)
    - Bill Franks, 2006 August 29; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002109973421)
    - Interview with Myles Antony re: John Stephen, 2007 May 21; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002109973439)
    - Interviews with John Stephen's Sister Rae and Bill Franks, 2007 January 09; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002109973454)
    - Bill Franks, 2006 October 5; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002109973462)
    - Myles Antony (John Stephen's art consultant) reminiscing on Carnaby St., 2007 September 30; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002109973470)
    - Interview with Mike McGrath at Wentworth Mansion re: John Stephen, 2007 March 23; 1 (Box 21, Item barcode 39002109973488)